Andres Felipe Baquero

Systems Engineer **Specialist in Software Development Processes**





+57 3137193752



afbaquerom@gmail.com



Cali, Colombia



<u>afbaquero</u>

PROFILE

Technical leader outstanding in Digital Transformation projects coordination with experience in planning, assignment and monitoring of activities. Extensive knowledge of Requirements Engineering, analysis, design, implementation and development of Business, Banking and Operational software, monolithic or distributed. Knowledge of agile methodologies and management of Java, .NET and Javascript programming languages, relational and non-relational databases, microservices, AWS and Icefaces, Primefaces, Spring Boot, Entity Framework, Devexpress, Angular and React development frameworks. Responsible person, with leadership and autonomy, ease of learning, good interpersonal relationships and goal-oriented.

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native

English: Intermediate

CERTIFICATIONS

SCRUM AGILE INSTITUTE SCRUM DEVELOPER 2013

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jan 2022 -Jan 2023

VOV SOLUTIONS

TECH LEAD

Description: Technical leader in projects and initiatives using Scrum methodology. Requirements engineering, Solution analysis, Communication design between different systems and applications, Base architecture design, Activities prioritization, Activities delegation, Applications implementation, Applications support, Data analysis, Code review.

Languages: Javascript. Database: MySQL, MongoDB.

Framework: ReactJS.

Tools: GIT, BitBucket, Jira, Clickup. Architecture pattern: Microservices. Platform: AWS, GCP, Terraform, Docker.

Methodology: Scrum. Development standards.

Obtained achievements:

- 1. Infrastructure Assembly in AWS for business project.
- 2. Delivery of application that processes e-mails.
- 3. Delivery of updates for clothing sales website.
- Delivery of updates for human resources portal.
- Implementation of improvements for event rental website.

Aug 2020 -Jan 2022

COOMEVA CORREDORES DE SEGUROS

IT DEVELOPMENT LEADER

Description: Technical leader in projects and initiatives using Scrum methodology. Requirements engineering, Solution analysis, Communication design between different systems and applications, Base architecture design, Activities prioritization, Activities delegation, Applications implementation, Applications support, Data analysis, Code review.

Languages: Java, JPA, JEE, EJB'S, Javascript, .NET.

Base de datos: DB2, SQL Server.

Framework: Icefaces, Spring Boot, Angular.

Tools: Maven, SVN, GIT, Jira.

Architecture pattern: MVC, Microservicios.

Platform: AWS. Methodology: Scrum. Development standards.

Obtained achievements:

- 1. Core system maintenance that manages the cooperative.
- 2. Contribution system maintenance for members of the cooperative through
- 3. Creation of two new products within the Core system that manages the cooperative.

PROJECTS

Mail processing system

Planning and assignment of activities. React JS, MySQL, BitBucket, AWS, GCP.

1 Year

VOV Solutions.

Clothing sales website

Planning and assignment of activities. React JS, MySQL, GitLab, AWS.

1 Year

VOV Solutions.

Human resources portal

Planning and assignment of activities. React JS, MongoDB, GitLab, AWS. 6 Months VOV Solutions.

Cooperative management system – SIPAS

Planning and assignment of activities. Java, Icefaces, DB2, SQL Server, JPA, EJB'S, Rest and Soap services, Maven, Subversion, GIT, JBoss 4.2, IDE Eclipse.

1 Year and 6 Months Coomeva Corredores de Seguros.

Cooperative product quotation system – SIMULADOR WEB

Planning and assignment of activities. Java, Spring Boot, Angular, DB2, SQL Server, JPA, EJB'S, Rest and Soap services, Maven, Subversion, GIT, Microservices, JBoss 4.2, JBoss 7.1, Javascript, IDE Eclipse, Spring Tools Suite.

1 Year and 6 Months Coomeva Corredores de Seguros.

Digital credit financing system – SIPRES PLUS

Scrum Master role. Java, .NET,
Oracle, SQL Server, JPA, EJB'S, Entity
Framework, Rest and Soap services,
Maven, Subversion, Weblogic 12c,
Javascript, IDE NetBeans 8, Visual
Studio 2017.

1 Year Fanalca S.A.

Motorcycle spare parts system - SIM

.NET, Oracle, SQL Server, Entity Framework, Devexpress, Subversion, Javascript, IDE Visual Studio 2017. 6 Months Fanalca S.A. Application evolution that generates the Dian reports for the cooperative members.

- **5.** Process implementation for generation of cooperative members payment reports.
- **6.** Published microservices maintenance through mediation for consume by external systems.

Jul 2015 – Aug 2020

FANALCA S.A.

DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Description: Scrum Master or Technical leader in projects and initiatives using Scrum methodology. Requirements engineering, Solution analysis, Communication design between different systems and applications, Base architecture design, Activities prioritization, Activities delegation, Applications implementation, Applications support, Data analysis.

Languages: Java, JPA, JEE, EJB'S, Javascript, .NET.

Database: Oracle, SQL Server.

Framework: Primefaces, Devexpress, Entity Framework.

Tools: Maven, SVN, GIT, Service Desk.

Architecture pattern: MVC. **Methodology:** Scrum. Development standards.

Obtained achievements:

- Digital credit financing system implementation integrating external databases through web services, processing an revenue validation flow and creating a communication between the logic and the form through Rest services.
- 2. Credit simulator implementation.
- **3.** Pre-settlement system integration with the Cifin risk center, which allows checking the customers payment habits.
- **4.** Customer viability model implementation, which allows calculating the customer compliance viability based on a series of data entered at the presettlement.
- **5.** Motorcycle logistics center management system implementation, with travel scheduling, inventory management, portfolio and production line.
- **6.** Administration and settlement freights implementation for motorcycle orders made in the ERP.
- **7.** Spare parts management system implementation for Honda motorcycles and cars.

Nov 2013 – Jul 2015

BANCO DE OCCIDENTE

PROFESSIONAL ANALYST

Description: Requirements engineering, Solution analysis, Activities prioritization, Applications implementation, Applications support, System test environments manager, Package software for installation in production.

Languages: .NET, Javascript, PL/SQL.

Database: Oracle.

Tools: SVN, IBM Rational ClearQuest, IBM Rational ClearCase, HP Service

Manager.

Development standards.

Obtained achievements:

- 1. Banking channel system parameterization.
- **2.** Audit implementation for the credit risk management system.
- 3. Solution design for the bank guarantees management.

Honda logistics system - LOGHO

.NET, Oracle, SQL Server, Entity Framework, Devexpress, Subversion, Javascript, IDE Visual Studio 2013. 1 Year and 1 Month Fanalca S.A.

Credit pre-settlement system – SIPRES WEB

Java, Oracle, JPA, JEE, EJB'S, Primefaces, Maven, Subversion, Weblogic 10, Javascript, IDE

NetBeans 8. 5 Years Fanal<u>ca S.A.</u>

Project audit system - ESPORA

.NET, Microsoft Visual Studio 2017, Oracle, Javascript. 11 Months

Fanalca S.A.

Credit risk management system – SARC

.NET, Microsoft Visual Studio 2006, Oracle, Javascript.

1 Year

Banco de Occidente S.A.

Banking System Channel Solution

.NET, Microsoft Visual Studio 2006, Oracle, Javascript.

6 Months

Banco de Occidente

Virtual product management system - Business NET

Java, Primefaces, JPA, JEE, EJB'S, Oracle, Maven, TeamCity, JBOSS, IDE

Eclipse Juno.

1 Year Codesa S.A.

Point of sale of virtual products - POS

Java, Primefaces, JPA, JEE, EJB'S, Oracle, Maven, TeamCity, JBOSS, IDE Eclipse Juno.

1 Year

Codesa S.A.

Product configurator

Java, Primefaces, JavaFX, JPA, JEE, EJB'S, Oracle, Maven, TeamCity, Tomcat, IDE Eclipse Juno.

6 Months Codesa S.A.

Survey generator system

Oracle, Javascript, IDE Oracle APEX. 11 Months Asistir S.A.

Survey system

Oracle, PHP, Javascript. 6 Months Asistir S.A. Nov 2012 – Nov 2013

CODESA S.A.

DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Description: Requirements engineering, Solution analysis, Communication design between different systems and applications, Base architecture design, Activities prioritization, Activities delegation, Applications implementation, Applications support, Data analysis.

Languages: Java, JPA, JEE, EJB'S, Javascript.

Database: Oracle.
Framework: Primefaces.
Tools: Maven, Teamcity, SVN.
Architecture pattern: MVC.
Methodology: Scrum.
Development standards.

Obtained achievements:

- 1. Virtual lotteries and products administrative system migration.
- 2. Lottery and virtual products POS system migration.
- 3. Virtual product configurator system implementation.

Dec 2011 – Oct 2012

ASISTIR S.A.

TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT

Description: Requirements engineering, Solution analysis, Applications implementation, Applications support, Database Administration.

Languages: PL/SQL, JavaScript.

Database: Oracle.

Tools: Oracle Application Express.

Obtained achievements:

1. Survey generating system implementation.

EDUCATION

Nov 2014 Degree Specialist in Software Development Processes

San Buenaventura Cali University

Feb 2013 Degree Systems Engineer

San Buenaventura Cali University

Jul 2007 Degree Technical Bachelor Computer Science Specialty

Leon de Greiff Cali School